# **Matthew Bridgeman CEng**

27 Northlands, Potters Bar, Hertfordshire. EN6 5DE.
Telephone: 07854 213 436 Email: matthewb.1@btinternet.com

Project Manager with over 8 years of professional experience managing and working on projects in the energy and steel industries. A qualified Prince 2 Practitioner, I manage a team of Project Engineers in the delivery of projects to supply a synthetic HFO, as well as a new biofuel, to marine and power generation clients.

## **Employment**

April 2016 – Present Quadrise Fuels – Project Manager

[previously: Project Engineer; Process Engineer]

I lead the Project Engineering team in the delivery of fuel projects for the marine and power industries. I report to the COO and am responsible for:

- Definition of project goals, scope and deliverables.
- Project planning, scheduling and documentation.
- Budget management including cost estimation and forecasting as well as oversight of procurement.
- Management of contractors and preparation and ownership of work packages.
- Management of quality and safety assurance.
- Presenting monthly project status overviews to the Board of Directors.

#### Recent projects include:

- Plant Installation/Commissioning Cepsa Refinery Project
  - o Installation of new MSAR® fuel production equipment at Cepsa's refinery in Algeciras, Spain.
  - o I managed each phase of the project from initial process design, through to EPC and commissioning.
  - o Project completed on time and under budget.
- Fuel Combustion Trials Morocco Industrial Client MSAR® Trial Programme
  - o I am managing a programme of MSAR® combustion trials on kilns across multiple sites in Morocco.
  - My ability to establish good working relationships with project stakeholders has proved vital in this
    role. I have pulled together know-how and experience of expert contractors, the original burner
    manufacturers and the client to produce work packages and oversee required modifications to the
    plants, including the design, EPC and commissioning of a new fuel handling system.
- Fuel Development Program bioMSAR™

I am project managing the fuel development programme for Quadrise's new marine biofuel. I am overseeing:

- The development and completion of a test matrix to produce a stable fuel at optimal cost at Quadrise's pilot plant.
- Creation of a fuel quality control programme, including construction of a marine test rig.
- o A comprehensive combustion testing programme (diesel engines and kilns).
- o Specification of new fuel booster modules for installation on vessels converting to bioMSAR™.

#### Other responsibilities at Quadrise include:

#### Business development

My role involves identifying, approaching and presenting to potential clients on Quadrise's technology and developing refinery-specific economic cases. I have written papers on synthetic fuels projects which I have presented at large industry events in Europe and the Americas. I am presenting on the progress made with bioMSAR™ projects to major conferences later this year (LARTC 2021 and ERTC 2021).

• Production Shift Management

I managed a shift of operators, engineers and chemists at the MSAR® fuel production unit in Spain.

September 2014 – April 2016 Amec Foster Wheeler – Process Engineer

IChemE accredited graduate scheme. Working on large engineering projects in the Middle East from Foster Wheeler's Reading office, I gained experience working within cross-functional project teams.

(September 2015 – April 2016)

Saudi Aramco Mobil Refinery Company (SAMREF), 2018 Turnaround Project, Saudi Arabia
I formed part of a small engineering team working on the Emergency Shut-Down System Replacement as part of the 2018 Turnaround Project at SAMREF Yanbu Refinery. I worked closely with Control and Instrumentation (C&I) specialists as well as the client to develop a new Fired Heater Safety system.

(September 2014 – August 2015)

Duqm Refinery and Petrochemical Industries Company (DRPIC), Duqm Refinery Project, Oman
I worked on the Front-End Engineering for the greenfield Duqm Oil Refinery Project. I formed part of the utilities team and, responsible for the refinery steam and condensate system, I gained experience in the core areas of chemical engineering. I wrote reports and developed documentation for the responsible areas, as well as performing engineering calculations. I also contributed to several multi-disciplinary health and safety reviews.

Based in Tata Steel's blast furnace technical department, I provided technical support to operators on-site. I led multi-discipline teams in the execution of process improvement projects:

- Investigating the possibility of increasing zinc (which can be damaging to blast furnaces) in raw materials to lower costs.
- Monitoring the effect of coke voidage on the flow of hot metal in the blast furnace hearth as part of a program that aimed to extend the campaign of the site's aging blast furnace.

# **Qualifications / Education**

- I am a Chartered Engineer with the Engineering Council and the Institute of Chemical Engineers (IChemE).
- I am a certified **Prince 2 Practitioner**.
- I have good proficiency in Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel) and Microsoft Project.

Sep 2009 – Jul 2014 University of Birmingham

Master of Engineering (MEng), Chemical Engineering, First-Class with Honours

Following my year-long industrial placement I was successful in winning sponsorship from Tata Steel.

Sep 2002 – Jun 2009 Nicholas Breakspear Catholic School

A Level: Biology [A], Chemistry [A], Mathematics [A] Head Boy: 2008-09

AS Level: German [B] GCSE: 8 A\*s, 2 As

## **Other Information**

- I hold a full, clean UK Driving License, as well as both British and Irish passports.
- As an active STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering and Maths) ambassador, I mentor A level students from disadvantaged backgrounds that are interested in a career in engineering.
- Passionate about sport, I play amateur level football and Gaelic football and am a qualified Level 7 Football Referee. I also compete in road running races and regularly watch my local football and cricket teams.
- Other interests include reading historical fiction novels, current affairs and watching live music and comedy.